Hi, everyone.
Welcome to your fast radio, but I wouldn't be talking about the v.C interface of Adobe Illustrator.
Right.
So Venu forced open your software.
This is the screen.
You would be welcome to it.
So the first thing you actually notice after welcome to Illustrator, it seems that you have to create
a new file.
Right.
So what this means is that you have to give dimensions.
All feel in your document on your document is your blank white page where you will be designing, audit
it all your illustrations.
Now, these illustrations can be either be used on your shots or your Mumbai Garbo's or on Mudd's or
even designed logos for your brand and even you and you when design GUI, log beaches, magazine, beaches,
bookstores, etc..
Right.
So if you need to choose from one of these documents right here, which are already being preloaded,
it can be off any size.
It can be a size of a postcard.
And even if you want to design and illustrate Dover, you can view on your phone the document can be
of this size as well.
But in case, if you want to also customize your document, even Fordo, you usually go to create new.
So as you can see right here, I do realize estate provides a much, much bigger good idea of these
documents right here.
So feel free to choose any of these documents ises as you please.
Feel free to even explore more options from Hill.
So the size is getting V.T. from any size, do any good people size, A4 size, Aletta letterhead,
tabloid format.
It's quite a lot.
But for this, where do I will be sticking to?
I will be sticking to this standard A4 size document, which is twenty one centimeters in weight and
twenty nine point seven centimeters in height.
So by default, in my laptop the unit of measurement is centimeters.
So in your screen it can be initially different.
Does what it might mean because all fixes or even inches it can maybe.
Okay here are instead of untied dude.
Let's also give a name to our document.
So let's Niemi Elias creation.
And here are the orientation part is basically how you want to use your document.
Do you want to do be in portrait format or do you want to do being landscape.
So it's up to you.
And over here are the art boards that sees and we are in the art board finder.
Right.
So it sees one that means only one document to a view or will be open.
When you only one document will be open for you to design.
I took a course, but you could always increase the number of outboards your.
Or it district to one.
And then we click on Clear.
And there you go.
This white Blankley's that you'll see is your documentary and you will be designing orda all your illustrations.
But in case, if you guys are unable to see all these that idea, it's probably because in short, in
this essential classic option at all.
Right.
So doing what if you aren't just click on this dropdown box below and click essentially classic.
So once you do that, all the tools you see right here will be shown.
OK.
So now let's begin.
So on your left hand side of your screen, all these tools you see right here are the mean do is that
we designed those.
You was 95 percent off.
Right.
So if you've seen those squawky designs up on finches, you've you seen mandalas or those complicated
gaited designs are used from these dudes.
Most of the times.
Right.
So moving ahead on the doc menu over here are all the other two words.
Red.
Right.
You can use to either to to your shape or if you want to add a particular type of effect you can to
choose any of these effects from your.
So if you want to change stuff fell off your collar.
So if you want to change the feel of your sheep, you can choose from these with ideal variety of colors,
a tail.
So this is the stroke.
The stroke is basically the outline of your sheet.
Right.
And over here are the short reed determines the intensity of your outline.
So by default, it's one that means the outline of your sheep will be extremely eaten.
So the higher the value of your stalk meat, the more tick I outline is going to be.
Right.
I know where you are on your right hand side of your screen.
Awesome.
Additional two words which are equally important for us designers to create all that illustrations.
Right.
So I will be discussing about these two with more in depth in the other videos as well.
But for now, as you can see, an audio design and illustration, you can control the John SPAD and
see from yo, you can decide how you going decide the opacity from your controller.
You can add different kinds of some votes from your even and even choose the type of brush size you
want from the from the brush to.
Right.
So this was it.
This was like the most basic introduction of the interface.
And that's about it.
So thank you for watching.
And I will see you again very soon.